in Alexander MS

☑ alexmserres@gmail.com
☐ +353 897011740

Alexander Mason Serres

PROFILE ----

I have recently graduated with a Bachelor of Science in **Applied Physics**, achieving **First-Class Honours**. I am currently employed as an **AI Software Engineer**, responsible for improving AI language models. I have recently been allocated into an exclusive group for the **highest quality** contributors within the company. I have over a year's experience as a **data analyst** within an energy project development company, primarily providing **data analytics** and designing software solutions to automate manual tasks. I have completed a certified **Google Data Analytics** course, developing my skills in **SQL**, **R**, and **Tableau**.

I am proficient in **python** programming with many functional projects completed. I also have extensive experience with **Excel**, **GIS**, **SQL**, and **LabView**. Given my physics background, I am very comfortable working with complex data and providing statistical and mathematical analysis. I am a driven individual and enjoy tasks which require research and problem solving.

SKILLS -

- Proven ability to deliver high quality technical work.
- Competent at many coding languages including Python, SQL, LabView, and Matlab.
- Extensive knowledge of calculus, differential equations and linear algebra.
- Strong problem solving skills with an ability to think analytically and logically.
- Over 1 year experience working **remotely**.
- Native English speaker and proficient at Portuguese.

EXPERIENCE ----

July 2024 – Present

Al Software Engineer

Outlier AI, Remote

- Enhancing the quality and accuracy of information provided by **Al language models** using **RLHF**.
- Reviewing and enhancing **Python**, **Swift**, **Java** and **SQL** code provided by Al language models to ensure it is optimized and functional.
- **Promoted** on multiple occasions to review and partake in final production stages.
- Assigned to an exclusive group of high quality contributors to work on advanced and high priority projects.

Lumcloon Energy, Ireland

- Producing reports and **data analytics** about potential renewable/ ancillary energy projects across Ireland.
- Optimised updating/ creating a database by creating automated python web-scraping programs to reduce the time to conduct early-stage project research.
- Brought about the development of a new **GIS** and **spatial database**, involving the creation of an extensive training course for the company.
- Developed an internal python program within GIS to **automate** the site selection process for energy projects based on infrastructure criteria.

Store Assistant

November 2018 - July 2021

Country Store, Ireland

- Responsible for stock rotation and stacking shelves, consistently ensuring a sufficient supply of products.
- Maintenance of the shop/ stock area & oversee deliveries of new products.

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS —

Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate

July 2024 - September 2024

Google Career Certificates, Remote

• Learning complete data analytics life cycle including data cleaning, manipulation, analysis and presentation using **SQL** and **R** languages.

Bachelor of Science in Applied Physics

September 2020 - May 2024

University of Limerick, Limerick, Ireland

- First Class Honours
- Core concepts of learning included Quantum Mechanics, Nanotechnology, Computational Physics, and Medical Instrumentation.
- Thesis: Completed a notable research project on **non-synchronous generation** within Ireland, using a physical model and a simulated environment.

Leaving Certificate

September 2019 - June 2020

Limerick Tutorial College, Limerick, Ireland

- Attained 512 points of a possible 625 points.
- Completed higher level Maths, Physics, Chemistry, Biology, English.